Campbell Collection of the Organization of Graduate Student Action
© 2010 University of Connecticut
Campbell Collection of the Organization of Graduate Student Action.
undated, 1991-2009.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Campbell, Barbara.
1.3 linear feet.
History, activities and related documentation of Organization for Graduate Student Action at the University of Connecticut and the mentor Connection.
MSS20090081
History
In 2003, University of Connecticut graduate assistants (GAs) were declared ineligible for the state employee health care plan under Governor John G. Rowland's "Back to Basics" budget. The OGSA was established to advocate on behalf of GAs for the restoration of their collective bargaining rights.
Scope and Content
Documentation of the organization established to advocate for health care benefits and employee status for graduate student assistants at the University of Connecticut.
Arrangement
The collection has received minimal processing and therefore remains in original order.
Inventory ( undated, 1991-2009 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Campbell, Barbara.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Fliers. [printed matter]
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Dr. Barbara J. Campbell in August 2009.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Inventory, undated, 1991-2009
  - (Box 1)
    - LAS 101 Mid-term paper, 2005
    - "Sounds of Silence,", undated
    - UConn Mentor Connection, 2008-2009
    - Armbands, 2003
    - General announcements and meeting agenda, 2003-2004
    - Essay contest fliers, undated
    - Graduate issues fliers, undated, 2003
    - Fliers and press releases, undated, 2003
    - Graduate student sign up sheets, undated
    - WHUS, "Under the Ivory Tower," transcript, undated
    - "Ivory Tower," Bousquet letter, 2004
    - "Ivory Tower," WHUS (91.7fm)Radio Show, undated
    - History of inclusion of GAs in state employee health benefits pool, 2003
    - RFP, includes addendum and breakdown of cost of current plan, 2003
    - Anthem certificate of coverage and correspondence, 2005
    - GA tuition fee increase, 2004-2005
    - Appendix B--very important, 2004
    - Contract letters, pay stubs, insurance card and information, 2002-2004
    - Testimonials--Personal impact of 2003 GA health insurance cut, 2004
    - GA Health Insurance timeline, undated
    - Newspaper clippings and press releases, 2003
    - University testimony and correspondence, 2003
    - Survey results and analysis, 2003
    - Delaware plan, 2003
    - UConn grad assistants, life insurance and DCAP, undated
    - Correspondence with Graduate Student Senate, 2002-2003
    - Correspondence with Graduate Student Senate, 2003-2006
    - Graduate Student Senate funding, undated, 2003-2004
    - Photocopies and notes, 2004
    - State employee status information, 2003
    - Petition, undated
    - Correspondence with Steve Weinberger and Mark Ojakian, 2004
    - Talking points, 2003
    - Appropriations, undated
    - Correspondence with Denise Merrill and Nyle Davey, 2003
    - Correspondence with Denise Merrill, 2003
    - Correspondence with Sandy Nafis, 2003
    - Public testimony, undated
    - Secretary of State meeting information, 2003
    - Sample letters, 2003-2004
    - Graduate assistant incomes, 2004
    - Contributions of UConn Graduate assistants, 2001-2004
    - AFSCME booklets, 2002-2004
    - English Graduate Student Association, 1991-2004